你已经来诺丁汉太多次了
You've come to Nottingham once too often.
今日之后  结果了你  我就不必再来了
After today, there'll be no need for me to come again.
你有事瞒着我
You've been holding out on me,
罗宾汉先生  我听说你有了心仪的男孩
Sir Robin. I hear you like a boy.
我就知道她保守不了秘密
I knew she'd tell.
那么这男孩是谁
So who is he?
他名叫欧文  是诗文班的
His name is Owen. He's in my poetry class.
很腼腆也很可爱
Very shy and very sweet.
-专心注意防守  -那就别让我分心
- Keep your guard up. - Then don't distract me.
-他知道你喜欢他吗  -不知道
- Does he know how you feel about him? - No!
为什么不呢
Why not? Ha! Hey!
因为我自己都不清楚对他的感觉
Because I don't even know how I feel about him.
好  很不错
Yes! Very nice!
他们为了把她给塞进去
How many bones did they have to break
得折断多少骨头
To get her in there?
在把她弄回实验室之前没办法知道
Won't know till I get her back to the lab.
别把案发现场弄脏了
Don't contaminate my crime scene.
不好意思  都是这些羽毛不好
Sorry, it must be the feathers.
贝克特到了
Beckett's here.
没有强行入室的迹象  和其他的一样
No sign of forced entry, same as the others.
似乎这些入侵者们
Looks like our home invasion crew
成功地4连击了
Went for a 4-peat.
他们正加快游戏节奏
They're stepping up their game,
变得更加残暴
Becoming more violent.
-保重  -扫把星
- Bless you. - Jinx.
他这是怎么了
What's wrong with him?
他对鹅毛过敏
Goose down. He's allergic.
抱歉  提下古老的扫把星游戏的规则
I'm sorry, I'm gonna time-honored rules of jinx.
在我赦免你之前  你不能说话
You are not allowed to speak untill I release you.
-保重  -保重
- Bless you. - Bless you.
翻转双倍扫把星(游戏双方地位颠倒)
Reverse double jinx.
我只是
I've just--I--
卡塞尔  在我赦免你之前闭上嘴
Castle, mouth shut until I release you.
谢了  莱恩
Thank you, Ryan.
有什么线索
So what do we have?
那是乔安·德尔加多
That's Joanne Delgado,
受害人苏珊·德尔加多的女儿
Daughter of Susan Delgado, the victim.
她打电话给她妈妈说晚安
She called to say good night to her mom.
不过今晚  她妈妈没有接电话
Only tonight, mom doesn't pick up.
她打电话给门卫  门卫上来查看
She calls the doorman. The doorman comes up,
发现门微开着  还有
Finds the door ajar and...
还有
And?
只能说这案子 绝对符合你的口味
Well, let's just say this one's Definitely Beckett-flavored.
血迹喷溅形态表明是一枪毙命
Blood spatter indicates single G.S.W.
近距离开枪  还可以闻到火药味
Close range. You can still smell the cordite.
我相信你的话
I'll have to take your word for it.
他们枪杀了她  再把她塞进保险柜里
Oh, they shot her and stuffed her in the safe.
比上起案件好多了
Better than the last one.
上起案子的受害人被活活打死
They beat the guy to death.
没有邻居听到枪声吗
None of the neighbors heard a gunshot?
没有  应该都睡得很死
Nada. Must be heavy sleepers.
不对  他们用了一个枕头
No, they used a pillow
就是穷人的消声器
As a poor man's sound suppressor.
好的  我触犯了扫把星的戒条
Yeah--yes, I broke the jinx.
请你喝汽水
I will buy you a soda.
-弹壳找到了吗  -没有
- Any shell casings? - None.
可能是左轮手枪  还用了剪线钳
Probably used a revolver. And a bolt cutter.
她的结婚戒指
Her wedding ring.
她不想拱手相让
She didn't want to give it up,
于是他们就惩罚了她
And so they punished her for it.
-丈夫呢  -几年前过世了
- Husband? - Passed a few years ago.
在这样的大宅里也会出事吗
In a building like this?
城里的这个区域应该是很安全的
This part of town, you'd think she'd be safe.
不是话中有话
No pun intended.
这样的街区
How often are people killed
凶杀率有多高
In neighborhoods like this?
和其他任何街区一样  卡塞尔
Same as anywhere else, Castle.
又多一起罢了
Just the once.
灵书妙探
第一季 第七集
每起劫杀的案发地点
Each of the robberies took place in
分属于不同的区域
A different part of the city.
不同的上流社区
A different high-end part of the city.
嵌入式保险箱和高档珠宝
Wall safes and high-end jewelry--
这些罪犯事前就有了
These guys came in knowing
明确的行窃目标
Exactly what they were gonna find.
这应该有个固有的模式
Well, there must be a pattern,
能把所有案件联系起来
Something that connects them all.
第一起案子是在三个月前吗
The first one was three months ago?
中央公园西街
Central park west
鲍勃·凯斯勒和琳达·凯斯勒
Bob and Linda Kesler
被绑住  塞住嘴巴  遭到殴打
Were bound, gagged and beaten.
罪犯戴着面具
Intruders wore masks.
劫走了大约价值17万5千的珠宝
Took roughly $175,000 in jewelry.
和约克街的那起作案模式相同吗
Same m.o. On York street?
是的  只是布鲁纳先生拒绝打开保险柜
Yeah, only when Mr. Bruner refused to open his safe,
劫匪就打断了他夫人的胳膊
They broke his wife's arms.
之后就是昨晚的案子了
Which brings us to last night.
他们越加猖狂了
They're getting bolder.
暴力行为正在升级
They're escalating their violence.
不会是随机选择作案对象的
Well, it can't be random.
他们怎么知道保险柜里有什么
How do they know what's in the safes?
保险柜  这是个词吗
"Safes"-- is that a word?
还是保检柜  应该不对
Is it "saves"? That can't be right.
你真是以写作为生的吗
And you write for a living?
卡塞尔  说重点
Castle, the point?
重点是  劫匪似乎
The point is, our home invaders seem to
对受害者颇为了解
Know an awful lot about our victims.
我们已经比对了保险公司
We've compared insurance companies,
家庭安防经销商
Home security vendors,
甚至是保险柜的种类
Even the kind of safes
可是没有对得上号的
That they had-- nothing's been a match.
我在想
I'm just thinking,
他们如此了解目标
They seem to know their targets so well,
或许他们真的认识受害人
Maybe they actually know them.
或许死者的女儿可以告诉我们
Maybe the victim's daughter can tell us.
是的  我们很亲
Yeah, we were close.
她是我母亲啊
She was my mother.
那她的朋友你都认识吗
So you'd know most of her friends?
她的朋友  是  但我
Her friends? Yeah, but I--
有没有你不大喜欢的
Were there any that you had strong feelings about,
或许是她最近在约会的人
Didn't like, maybe someone she met recently?
没有
No.
她有没有朋友有经济问题
Did any of her friends have money problems?
那些畜生破门而入杀害了她
Monsters broke into her place and killed her.
你们了解她的朋友做什么
Why are you asking about her friends?
认识尼尔森·布鲁纳和珍妮特·布鲁纳吗
Do you know Nelson and Janet Bruner?
不认识
No.
理查德·帕斯托利和朱莉·帕斯托利呢
How about a, uh, Richard and Julie Pastori
还有鲍勃·凯斯勒和琳达·凯斯勒
Or a bob and Linda Kesler?
这些人都是谁
Who are these people?
他们是前三起
They're victims of three previous
入室劫案的受害者
Home invasion robberies.
我们觉得这三起案子的劫匪
Robberies that we think
和杀害你母亲的凶手
Were committed by the same people
是同一伙人
That murdered your mother.
还有别的劫案吗  我说
There were others? I mean...
类似的案件发生有多久了
How long has this been going on?
几个月了
A few months.
几个月
Months?
什么  你们还没抓到这帮畜生吗
What, and you haven't caught them yet?
上周之前他们还没杀人
They didn't murder anyone until last week.
所以我上周才接手这案子
That's when I got this case, and since then,
我们一直在尽最大的努力
We have been doing everything we can to--
不  别和我说这些空话了
No, don't press-conference me, detective.
我本人就在公共关系部工作
All right, I work in public relations.
所以省省你那套说辞吧
So you can save your speech
因为类似的话我已经听得太多了
Because I have heard them all, all right?
空难和大肠杆菌中毒事件后
I'm the one who drafts all of that pathos
给死难者的悼词都是我起草的
After airline crashes and e. Coli poisonings.
"我们同情受害者的家人"
"Our--our hearts go out to the victims' families."
同情
Our hearts?
这种话的有什么意义
What does that even mean?
她说她想做些烘焙烹饪
She said that she felt like baking.
她要我过去  但我那时很忙
She want me to come over, but I was busy.
我那时很忙
I was busy.
而现在她死了
And now she's dead.
乔安  听我说
Joanne... Listen to me.
接下来的几天
You're gonna want to
你可能一直会想
Play out every possible scenario
每一种可能的场景
In the next couple of days--
如果你当时在那里
If only you'd been there,
如果你当时顺路经过
If only you'd come by,
如果你没有工作得那么晚
If only you didn't work so late.
我告诉你  这不是你的错
And I'm telling you, it's not your fault.
只能怪那些畜生一样的罪犯
The ones to blame are the monsters
杀害你妈妈的凶手
That murdered your mom.
这不是说辞  也不是陈词滥调
This isn't a speech. It's not a platitude.
这是一个承诺
It's a promise.
我会尽我所能
I am going to do everything in my power
确保那些人会为其罪行付出代价
To make sure that they pay for what they did.
真的很感人
It's pretty impressive,
你应付她的方式
The way you handled her back there.
我并不是在应付她  卡塞尔
I didn't "handle" her, castle.
我只是和她说实话
I just told her the truth.
和我要对其他受害者
The same thing I'm gonna tell
所说的话一样
The other home invasion victims.
扫把星的债全清了
Jinx paid in full.
这是工作  卡塞尔
It's the job, Castle.
你这是在抛售  贝克特
Oh, you're short-selling, Beckett.
莱恩和埃斯波西托
Ryan and Esposito
就没这么将心比心
Could not manage that level of empathy.
才不是
That's not true.
他们把劲头都放橄榄球游戏上了
They just save it for fantasy football trades.
让我想起了阿丽克西斯
Makes me think about Alexis.
我要是有什么不测  她怎么办
What would she do if something happened to me?
还有她妈妈  不是吗
Well, she still has her mom, right?
梅瑞狄斯更像是
Meredith is more like a
手持信用卡的疯阿姨
Crazy aunt with a credit card.
我才是两人间更负责的那个
Of the two of us, I'm the more responsible one.
听起来真凄惨  对吧
Pretty sad, isn't it?
要是我就不会担心那么多  卡塞尔
Well, I wouldn't worry about it too much, castle.
毕竟  好人才不长命
After all, only the good die young.
听着  弗洛伊德  我知道你要做什么
Listen, Freud, I know what you're trying to do.
你想让我谈谈我妈
You're trying to get me to talk about my mom,
看看能不能从我口中挤出
See if you can squeeze any more pulp
对你的低俗小说有用的料
For your fiction.
低俗小说  你认为我写的都是低俗小说
Pulp? You think what I do is pulp?
听着  我会让你知道
Listen, I will have you know
《纽约书评》
That "the New York Review of Books"--
小提示  不是《纽约时报书评》
Not "the New York Times Book Review," mind you--
《纽约书评》说了
"The New York review of books" said that
德里克·斯道姆系列是这一代人的回应
Derrick Storm is this generation's answer to
我看过那书评
I read that piece,
就算是你也不得不承认
And even you have to admit
那说法有点过于夸张了
That it's more than a little hyperbolic.
你给了评论家多少钱呢
So how much did you pay the reviewer?
一大箱的教皇新堡红酒
A case of ChateauNeuf-du-Pape.
但那不是重点  重点是
But that's not the point. The point is,
你也看《纽约书评》吗
You read "The New York Review of Books"?
贝克特警探裹着这么多层神秘面纱
Oh, so many layers to the Beckett onion.
你怎样才能一一揭开呢
How ever will you peel them all?
埃斯波西托  其他受害者有什么消息吗
Esposito, anything from the other victims?
贝克特去市区完成调查去了
Beckett's downtown finishing the canvass,
但我们现在所知的是
But what we do know is,
凯斯勒夫妇和帕斯托利夫妇
The Keslers and the Pastoris
彼此不认识
Didn't know each other,
他们也不认识
And neither one of them knew
布鲁纳夫妇或苏珊·德尔加多
The Bruners or Susan Delgado.
从个人关系上查只能查出这么多了
Well, so much for the personal angle.
四座豪华大宅  四起大案子
Four luxury buildings, four major scores,
我们却寸步难行
And we got nothing.
如果我是劫匪
If I'm these guys,
现在也没理由收手
I got no incentive to quit now, either.
好吧  不管他们是谁
Yeah, well, whoever they are,
他们肯定有合理的入室理由
They definitely have some righteous trade skills.
说到这个  鉴证人员刚从
About that-- forensics just came back
德尔加多的房子里回来
On the Delgado's' place.
他们在前门的门锁处
They found brass shavings
发现了黄铜的碎屑
In the lock mechanism on the front door.
黄铜碎屑吗
Brass shavings?
他们用了把万能钥匙
They used a bump key.
凶手挫掉门锁
Bad guys file down a stanwestie house key,
然后用一把木槌把它敲进锁孔里
Then they use a mallet to drive it in the lock.
锁芯就像台球一样一撞四散
Separates the tumblers like billiard balls.
伙计  我知道什么是万能钥匙
Hey, man, I know what a bump key is.
你不知道
No, you don't.
德尔加多的门锁
The hardware on the Delgado's' door
可是高档的进口货
Was a high-end import.
普通的万能钥匙不可能行得通
No way standard bump key would work.
他们得用些特殊的工具
No, they'd have to use something special,
不是普通的匪盗配备得起的
Something the average mope couldn't rig.
你怎么想
What do you think?
我不久前抓过一个家伙
I busted this guy a while back,
用万能钥匙作案  胆大包天
Specialized in bump keys, and he's not afraid
还出手伤人
To get a little blood on his paws, either.
万能钥匙和暴力  我已经喜欢上他了
Bump keys and violence? I like him already.
-埃文·米切尔  -埃文·米切尔
- Evan Mitchell. - Evan Mitchell?
你认识他吗
Yeah. You know him?
他出身世家啊
He's a legacy.
他爸爸和他爷爷
His dad and his Grand-dad
都是这一行的传奇人物
Are legends in the industry.
我在47街抓住他盗窃珠宝
Yeah, I collared him on a jewel heist on 47th.
是个乡下恶棍
Just did a nickel upstate.
米切尔什么时候获释
When did Mitchell get out?
第一起案子案发两周前
Two weeks before our first heist.
把他抓起来
Pick him up.
和他的小朋友问个好吧
Say hello to his little friend.
找到他的时候  他腰里正别着
It was in his waistband when we snatched him up.
序列号被磨掉了
Serial numbers are scratched off.
罪行重  但定罪轻
Heavy on collars, light on convictions.
被抓那么多次却次次脱罪
Amazing how many times a guy can get arrested
也真是奇了
Without ever serving time.
他一定有个好律师
He must have a pretty good lawyer.
或者说他是个老手
Or good at what he does.
够格做我们的嫌犯吗
Good enough to be our perp?
你们作家为什么总叫他们"嫌犯"
Why do you writers always call 'em "perps"?
你们不就是这么叫的吗
Isn't that what you call them?
不知道  我们的叫法多了去了
I don't know. We got a whole lot of names for 'em.
瘾君子  酒鬼  丑八怪  烂人
Pipehead, pisshead, ork, creep...
骗子  蠢蛋  呆子
Crook, knucklehead, chucklehead...
-笨蛋  屎人  -破坏狂  流浪汉
- Chud, turd... - Destro, skell...
怪兽  淫棍  滑头
Skeksi, slicko, slick...
-混混  -妖兽
- Mope. - Sleestack.
慢点说  慢点说
Slow down, slow down.
嫌疑人
Suspects.
我们叫他们嫌疑人
We call them suspects.
我是老派人  我喜欢说无耻之徒
I'm old-school. I like dirtbag.
经典啊
Classic.
和我说说枪的事  米切尔先生
Tell me about the gun, Mr. Mitchell.
没有律师在场我是不会开口的
Well, I'm not talking without a lawyer.
为什么  你难道为某事而心虚吗
Why? Are you guilty of something?
你们的人出现时
Yeah, of not running fast enough
没来得及跑掉
When your boys showed.
昨晚5点到9点你在哪里
Where were you last night between 5:00 and 9:00?
我什么也没干
I didn't do it.
-你没干什么  -任何事
- You didn't do what? - It doesn't matter what.
无论你认为我在哪里
Wherever you think I was,
我都不在
I wasn't.
你到底在哪里
So where were you then?
快乐时光
Happy hour.
在酒馆  约上几个老友
Little neighborhood place drinking
喝着贝尔法斯特鸡尾酒
Belfast car bombs with some of my westie pals.
有人证明吗
You got anyone that can verify that for me?
大约30人可以证明
Yeah. I got about 30 people or so can.
这还是保守估算
Conservative estimate.
可直觉告诉我  这里面大部分人
How come I got this crazy hunch that most of
都像你一样有前科
Those people got records a lot like yours?
我确实没在广场喝茶
Well, I wasn't drinking tea at the plaza.
想要可靠的证人吗
Look, you want more reliable witnesses?
给我1小时吧  我会尽力找的
Give me an hour or so, I'll see what I can do.
可需要铁关系
Must be pretty well connected.
或者高层有朋友
Friends in high places.
这个女人气十足的家伙是谁
Who's married with the manicure?
那发型  一看就知道不是警察
I know he's not a cop, not with that haircut.
我协助贝克特探长
I'm assisting Detective Beckett
查案
In the investigation.
协助吗  怎么啦  宝贝
Assisting? What's the matter, sweetie?
自己搞不定吗
You can't hack it out there alone?
想玩玩吗
You wanna play?
如你所愿
Let's play.
我抓到有前科又有枪
I got an ex-con with a gun
手上还有两宗谋杀案还没结
And two fresh homicides just looking for a home.
警长  尽管钓你的鱼
You can fish all you want, Detective.
聪明的鱼不咬饵
Smart fish don't bite.
虽然可以因为持枪扣留他
We could hold him on the gun, there's no match
可他的枪与杀害德尔加多夫人的枪不符
With ballistics on Mrs. Delgado.
如果找不到其他证据
And without other evidence
证明他与另外一起案件有关
To link him to the other homicide-
长官  我会找到证据的
I'll find something, sir.
可是不在场证明确凿  就别查了
Not if his alibi checks out.
长官  那都是障眼法
Sir, it's just pots and kettles.
不是第一起  是最后那起案子
On the last robbery, not the first.
恰好在同一天  米切尔被提审
Mitchell was being arraigned on
不过  不是这个案子
An unrelated burglary
他涉嫌偷窃另一处
The same day this crew struck.
除非推翻这个不在场证明
Unless you can break his alibi on this one,
否则  他这条路走不通
He's a dead end.
小心这些人影
You gotta watch those silhouettes.
他们也可能是些狡诈的混蛋
They can be shifty little bastards.
如果不介意  我想集中精神
Do you mind? I'm trying to concentrate.
老兄  我遇到瓶颈时
Man, when I hit a wall, all I got
就捏捏压力球或上网看看黄片
Is stress ball and internet porn.
卡塞尔
Castle-
听着  我很理解
Look, I get it, all right? You made a promise
你向女儿保证要抓住凶手
To a daughter to find her mother's killer.
虽然我不是弗洛伊德  也明白这道理
It doesn't take Freud to see what's what.
走出迷宫之前
But you're gonna run up some blind alleys
你势必要走些冤枉路
Before you get out of the maze.
听着  非常感谢你说的
Look, as much as I appreciate
菲力博士[脱口秀节目主持人]的格言警句
Your folksy Dr. Phil Aphorisms,
我只想
I just wanna-
如果他们不是那么乖乖地站着
Wouldn't it be more of a challenge
不是更有挑战性吗
If they weren't standing still?
卡塞尔  让我见识你的本事
Okay, Castle. You show me how it's done.
看你的了
All yours.
这不是决斗  胆小鬼
It's not a duel, Scaramouch.
这样
Here.
面对枪靶站好
Square off to the target.
双脚打开  与肩同宽
Feet shoulder-distance apart.
好的  用你左手掌
Okay. Gauntlet your right fist
托住右手
In your left palm.
枪开早了
Shot too soon.
我们可以经常这样抱一下  卡塞尔
You know, we could always just cuddle, Castle.
很有意思
Oh, funny.
你笑了  很好
And a smile. Good.
好点了
That's better.
我其实
You know, I, uh,
下来是想问问你
Came down to ask you if I could, uh,
可否把失窃物的照片带回家
Take home some of those stolen property photos.
珠宝的照片  为什么
Photos of the jewelry? Why?
现在还说不上来
I don't know.
只是觉得可能蕴含什么
I just thought it might spark something.
-肯定疼  -听好了
- That kinda hurt. - Tell you what.
如果你在三枪之内打中十环
You put any of the next three in the ten ring,
-我就把资料给你  -当真
- And I will give you the files. - Yeah?
当真
Yeah.
你真是个好教练
You're a very good teacher.
爸爸
Hey, dad.
你和欧文的约会怎么样
Hey, how was your date with Owen?
爸爸  我们那是学习小组  不是约会
Dad, it wasn't a date. It was a study group.
小组有几个人
Okay, how many in the group?
只有我们两个
Just the two of us.
又把证据偷回家
Pilfering evidence again, I see.
借的  这些只是复本
Borrowing. And these are just copies.
保险公司会保留
Insurance companies like to maintain
这类物品的认证照片
Photos of pieces like these for identification
以防遭窃或丢失
In case anything gets lost or stolen.
真是太美了
Hello, gorgeous! Ooh!
你们怎么没走进我的生活呢
Where have you been all my life?
我在想是不是应该装一套
You know, I'm thinking of installing
新的保安系统  建个密室
A new security system, maybe even a panic room.
密室有什么用  怕恐怖袭击吗
Panic room? What for, panic attacks?
如果有坏人
If anyone comes,
我们用武力解决
We'll beat them off with swords.
或者用文字  比武力更强大
Or pens, since they're mightier.
不  我没开玩笑  我要你们平平安安
No, I'm serious. I just want us to be safe.
生活哪里会风平浪静  更何况是在纽约
Oh, life isn't safe, especially not in New York-
起重机突然倒塌
Cranes collapse,
空调机从天而降
Air conditioners fall out of the sky.
到头来  人生只剩短短数年
In the end, there's just a few short years.
在死于非命之前
The most you can do is make the most of it
不如充分利用这短暂的时光
Before something knocks you down.
活得充实  对死亡毫无畏惧
"People living deeply have no fear of death."
阿娜伊丝·宁的话吗
Anais Nin?
妈妈  您还有多少存货
Mother, how many of those have you had?
这可是无价之宝
These are pretty incredible pieces.
普通的防盗手段不够
You wouldn't use a normal fence for these.
此人要具有上乘的品味
You'd need someone with impeccable taste,
清楚这些宝贝的价值
Someone who appreciated their value,
还得找到出得大手笔的买家
Someone who had high-end buyer connections.
鲍威尔
Powell.
记得这个人吗
Oh, now there was a man.
你可把人家毁了
And you had to ruin it.
-鲍威尔是谁  -很多年前的事啦
- Who's Powell? - That was years ago.
他肯定全忘了
I'm sure he's forgotten all about that.
鲍威尔是谁
Who's Powell?
怎么忘  你逼得他隐退江湖
Forgotten? You forced him into retirement.
毁了他的人生
You ruined his life.
他威胁要宰了你
He threatened to slit your throat.
爸爸  谁是鲍威尔
Dad, who's Powell?
记得我小说里有个人物
You remember that character of mine-
宾利·西沃
Um, Bentley Silver?
《风暴骤起》里面的珠宝大盗
The jewel thief in "Storm Rising"?
某种程度上  以鲍威尔为原型
Yeah, I kinda based him on Powell.
某种程度  你盗走了人家的一生
Kind of? You stole the man's entire life,
然后你的天才父亲
And then your father, genius that he is,
在致谢里  指名道姓感谢他
Thanked him in the acknowledgments,
完全把人家曝了光
Completely blowing his cover.
他不会还在生气的
Yeah, he can't still be mad.
我这就去看看他
I'm gonna go see him.
老爸
Dad!
别担心  我不会有事的
No, I'll be okay. Don't worry.
我觉得应该不会出事
I think it'll be fine.
如果他没让你断气
If he doesn't slit your throat,
提醒他  在马戏团[纽约顶级餐厅]欠我一顿
Tell him he owes me an evening at Le Cirque.
老爸  老爸
Dad! Dad!
为这拳我已经等候多时了  卡塞尔
I have been waiting a long time for this, Castle.
怎么说呢  里克
What can I say, Rick?
你确实欠扁
You really had it coming.
说得对  多谢放我一条生路
Yes, I did. Thanks for not killing me.
这条地毯是件古董
The carpet's an antique...
16世纪中期产于土耳其
Turkish, mid-1600s.
沾上一滴血也是重大损失
A blood stain on it would've been a disaster.
还有  我准备洗手不干了
Besides, I was ready to retire.
当鬼影应该是年轻人的游戏
Being a ghost is a young man's game.
很高兴再见  老朋友
Good to see you again, old friend.
我也很高兴  亲爱的孩子
And you, as well, dear boy.
玛莎怎么样
Tell me, how is Martha?
还在上演没有观众的独角戏
Still a one-woman show in search of an audience.
她说  在马戏团餐厅你还欠她一顿
She says you owe her an evening at le cirque.
我哪会有这种荣幸
And to what do I owe the pleasure?
不会是你又要写个后续
You're not planning a sequel, I hope.
什么东西
What's this?
失窃的珠宝
Stolen jewelry
都是入室盗窃被盗的
From that rash of home invasions.
美极了
So very lovely.
有没有人要把这些东西出手
I was wondering if anyone's tried to fence them.
圈子里倒是没听到风声
I've heard nary a whisper of anything in this range.
警方抓到个家伙叫米切尔
The police are holding a guy named Mitchell.
没见过
Haven't had the pleasures.
它们有什么特别
Anything special about these?
有共同之处吗
Anything they have in common?
这些珠宝极少佩戴
These are hardly everyday wear.
我敢说  不是在特殊场合
I suppose one dusts them off
这些珠宝不会轻易示人
For that very special occasion.
那窃贼怎么知道珠宝藏在哪里
So then how did our thieves know they were there?
见财起意  里克
Seeing comes before wanting, Rick.
这些家伙
These chaps...
可能就生活在被害人身边
May actually live among their victims
属于一个圈子
And move through their world.
还有什么地方与众不同
Anything else special about them?
看不到现场
Without seeing the scene of the crime,
一切只是推测而已
Anything more would be mere speculation.
犯罪现场已经封锁了
Well, the crime scene's all locked and sealed.
没法让你进去
I don't think I could get you in there.
不用为此操心
Let that be the least of our concerns.
看来  你的技术一点没生疏
You, uh, don't seem out of practice.
像骑自行车一样
Just like riding a bike.
盗贼使用万能钥匙
Our thieves used a bump key.
这些晚辈真是粗俗至极
This new generation... How utterly vulgar.
里克
Rick...
你没说他们把她塞进了保险箱
You didn't tell me they put her in the safe.
重要吗
What's the significance?
要点在
The significance...
是否有这个必要
Is it's unnecessary.
凶残是因凶残的本质而起
It's brutality for brutality's sake.
这本来是绅士的游戏
This used to be a gentlemen's game.
我们本来如同鬼影
We were like ghosts.
轻易而举的穿墙而过  来无影去无踪
We could walk through walls and simply disappear.
可干出这种事的家伙
But whoever did this...
更像吸血鬼
They're more like vampires.
看到血才有精神
Just the blood makes them feel alive.
这些人
These aren't the sort of chaps
不像做我们这行的人
A fellow in my line of work
大家避免在黑暗里撞上
Would care to meet by chance in the dark.
撞上的次数多吗
How often does that happen?
要比你想象得多
More often than you'd think, actually.
我们的活动范围很小
Ours is a very small community.
碰上了怎么办
And then what?
我那时候
In my day,
彼此间会达成某种默契
We'd usually come to some sort of an agreement.
对职业人士
You see, there was a code
有着行动守则
Of conduct among professionals.
鲍威尔  鲍威尔
Powell. Powell.
卡塞尔
Castle?
怎么了
Hey. What's going on?
你带个盗贼去犯罪现场
You brought a thief to a crime scene.
帮助很大
It was very helpful.
那是擅闯犯罪现场
It was criminal trespassing.
没什么差别
To-may-toh, to-mah-toh.
告诉你朋友别再现身了
Tell your friend to keep up his disappearing act.
如果下次你再去犯罪现场
And the next time
没有叫我同行的话
You show up at a crime scene without me,
让你尝尝我的泰瑟枪
I'll show you how my taser works.
一言为定
Promise?
你到那里干什么
So why were you there?
看看遗漏了什么
Seeing if there's anything I missed.
所以呢
So?
所以什么
有遗漏的地方吗
Was there?
米切尔保释了吗
Did Mitchell make bail yet?
还差一份书面材料
Paperwork's not done yet.
扣着他就想出口恶气
I'm holding him out of spite.
我想跟他谈谈
I want to talk to him.
为什么  我们都知道他与此无关
Why? We already know he wasn't involved.
凭借鲍威尔说的话
Something Powell said.
我觉得米切尔掌握些情况  只是没说出来
I think Mitchell knows more than he's saying.
那你又凭什么认为他会说出来呢
And what makes you think he'll share it with us?
只是我  而非我们
Not us. Just me.
你是干什么的
So what are you?
法医精神病学家  还是心理侧写师
A forensic psychiatrist, some kind of profiler?
我实际上是个作家
Actually, uh, I'm a writer.
警队的随团记者吗
An embedded reporter, huh?
想帮我成名吗
What, are you gonna make me famous?
不是那种作家  我是小说家
Not that kind of writer. I'm a novelist.
是吗  有没有我可能看过的
Yeah? Uh, anything that, uh, I might've heard of?
《风暴终焉》
Uh... "Storm's Last Stand."
《暴风季节》
"Storm Season."
德里克·斯道姆
Derrick Storm?
-是的  -我挺喜欢那家伙
- Yeah. - I love that guy.
为什么非得弄死他
Why the hell did you kill him?
说来话长了  我现在在写一部新作
It's a long story, but I'm working on a new one.
我得说  那部作品真是不错
And I gotta tell you, it is very cool.
我想写清楚细节
But I want to get the details right.
细节从来都写不对
They never get the details right
无论是书里的还是电影的
Not in books, movies.
我们总会被描写为流氓强盗
They always write us as clowns and thugs.
他们不曾想过
They never stop to think that
我们也要还贷款和照顾家人
Maybe we got mortgages, families...
确实  那我这新书中
Exactly. Okay, so... In the new book,
会写到一伙入室抢劫团伙
It's about this crew of home invaders,
以我们正在搜寻的犯罪团伙为原型
Based on the crew we're looking for right now.
有个情节是一个像你的角色
I got this one scene where a guy just like you
阴差阳错地撞见了他们
Runs into these guys by accident
在一次作案过程中
In the middle of a job.
我不会遇到这种事
Wouldn't happen to me.
我不会在住宅区作案
I'm not doing residentials.
至少在你把那些人抓起来之前不会
Not at least until you catch these guys.
那些人都是道上的人
These guys are dark.
什么  你知道他们是谁吗
What, you know 'em?
几个月前  他们老大来过酒吧
Their shot caller came into the bar a few months back
找一些合伙人
Looking to put together a crew.
想我要加入  说他有耳目在内
Wanted to bring me on, said he had eyes inside
为他策划
Working up scores for him,
给他一些重要信息
Feeding him the glengarry leads-
行窃物品  姓名  地址
Items, names, addresses.
他就想要我的万能钥匙
Said that all he needed was one of my bump keys.
你有给他吗
Did you give it to him?
是  我给他要是只是为了摆脱他
Yeah, I gave it to him, but just to get rid of him.
我可不打算加入他的团伙
I wasn't about to join his crew.
真糟糕
I'll be damned.
-为什么不  -我说了  那些人是道上的人
- Why not? - Like I said, these guys were dark.
我是速战速决  偷了就走
And I'm a 2-minute man, in and out.
这是我个人坚持的原则
That's my one hard-and-fast.
但是这活太残酷血腥了
But this sadistic whack job?
他说他喜欢在吃之前
Whoa. He said he liked to play
戏弄猎物的感觉
With his food before he ate it.
那这个老大
All right, this, um, this shot caller...
如果要写进书里
If I put him in the book,
就得尽可能地写实
I want it to feel authentic.
那他长成什么样
How would you describe him?
这是杀她的凶手吗
This is the man who killed her?
我们认为是的
We think so.
我们认为他与你妈妈
We believe he may have had more than just
曾经有过联系
A passing relationship with your mom.
他可以是任何人  服务生  遛狗的
And he could be anyone. A waiter, dog walker,
门卫  私人教练
Doorman, personal trainer...
不  我不认识他
No, I don't recognize him.
也许其他受害人知道
Maybe one of the other victims knows?
你妈经常佩戴珠宝吗
Your mom wear jewelry often?
不  只有重大场合
No, just to special events.
什么样的重大场合
What kind of special events?
去年的时装发布会
Uh, a fashion show last year...
画廊开业  慈善募捐
Gallery openings, fund-raisers...
我妈热心于各种活动
My mother loved her causes.
比如歌剧团  环保组织
You know, opera companies, environmental groups...
内部眼线
Eyes inside.
我们为什么要重新梳理案情
Why are we doing this again?
根据米切尔所说
Well, according to Mitchell,
那个要万能钥匙的家伙
The shot caller who wanted the bump key
有眼线可以给他提供
Had someone feeding him inside information
受害者的情况
About our victims.
鲍威尔也说  被偷的珠宝
And Powell says the pieces of jewelry being stolen
是为重大场合而珍藏的
Are the kind you save for special occasions.
重大场合  比如慈善晚会
Special occasion, like a charity event.
所以我们要找一个组织
So we find an organization
我们所有的受害者都参与其中
That all of our victims supported.
然后我们就将找到罪犯
And we find our guy.
德尔加多和帕斯托利都参加
Delgado and Pastori both gave
一个曼哈顿的歌剧协会
To the Manhattan opera society.
但是不包括最后两个受害者
But not the last two victims.
三个家庭都捐助了美国艾滋病协会
I got three families that donated to a.i.d.s. America
德尔加多  布鲁纳和凯斯勒
Delgado, Bruner and Kesler.
但是没有帕斯托利
But not Pastori.
也许帕斯托利是三个受害家庭之一
Maybe Pastori was a guest
邀请的客人
Of one of the other three victims.
不  这些家庭互不相识
No, none of the families knew each other.
等等  大都会剧院
Wait a second. M.A.D.T.-
就是美国大都会歌舞剧院
That's the Metropolitan American Dance Theater.
美国大都会歌舞剧院
Metropolitan American Dance Theater.
Metro American Dance...M.A.D.T.
这就是 嫌犯从中获利的  那个非盈利性机构
That's the non-Profit our invaders are profiting from.
去查谁是负责人
Find out who was in charge
-和联系方式  -立刻查
- And how I can find them. - Right on.
查到了
There she is.
安妮·格林  公司负责人
Anne Greene, the company's director.
她随时可能入侵我家
She can invade my home anytime.
如果她有参与
Yeah,oh. She is in on it,
也只是为了取乐
She's doing it purely for kicks.
纺织业继承人  没有前科
Textile heiress, no record and clean dmv.
白色的放在天使装饰的桌上
White centerpieces go on angel tables.
红色的放在赞助者席上
Red centerpieces go on sponsor tables.
格林小姐  我是贝克特探长
Ms. Greene, I'm detective Beckett,
-这位是  -里奇  里奇·卡塞尔
- And this is - Ricky? Ricky castle?
我听过你不少事迹呢
I've heard perfectly all of things about you
-从我朋友切尼那听说  -切尼
- From my friend Cheney. - Cheney?
高个  浅褐色皮肤  人工鼻梁
Tall, brunette, aftermarket nose.
切尼  想起来了  她还好吗
Cheney... Of course. How is Cheney?
我听说她在圣莫里茨[瑞士]绯闻不断
Oh, I hear she's a great scandal in st. Moritz.
那你呢
Oh. And you?
目前正好单身
Currently between scandals, actually.
那你们不是
Oh, you two aren't...
-还不是  -不是
- Not yet. - No.
永远不可能  其实里奇只是协助我
Never. In fact, um, Ricky here is assisting me
调查一桩谋杀案
With a homicide investigation.
真刺激
How exciting.
不错  现在案子跟你的组织有关了
Yes, and it involves your organization.
我们所有的雇员都经过了
All of our employees go through
严格的背景核查
An extensive background check.
我可以保证
I can assure you
他们不会牵涉其中的
None of them are involved.
我还是需要你提供一份雇员名册
I'm still gonna need a list of the employees
-可以接触到捐资者记录的雇员  -好吧
- Who had access to donor records. - Of course.
探长  我觉得这都是巧合
Detective, I'm sure this is all a coincidence.
但是  我并不这么觉得  所以
Unfortunately, I'm not, and that's why
我仍需要一份捐助者名单副本
I'm gonna need a copy of your donor list.
这就有问题了
That may be a problem.
有些人的身份是公开的  那还没问题
The people who give publicly, they're not an issue.
但是我们有些捐助者是匿名的
But some of our donors cherish their anonymity.
我们是要依约保守秘密
We're contractually obligated to protect that.
那不管他们死活吗
What about their lives?
你的捐助者也不在乎性命吗
Do your donors cherish those, as well?
我保证  我的员工会联络每个捐助者
I assure you, my office will contact each of them
并提醒他们注意安全
And alert them to the situation.
我想我可以去负责通知他们
I'd really like to contact them myself.
我很抱歉  探长  我没有这个权利
I'm sorry, detective, but my hands are tied.
如果你想要我们的保密名册
If you want my confidential donor list,
你要拿到法庭许可令
You're gonna need a court order.
尴尬
Awkward.
我们调查了雇员和志愿者
We ran employees and volunteers.
没有人有犯罪记录
None have priors or records.
她在干什么
What's she doing?
写法庭许可令的申请报告
Writing an affidavit for a court order.
不会有人签署的
That no one is going to sign.
看了董事会成员名单吗
Did you see that list of board members?
城里一半的法官都名列其上
Half the judges in town are on it.
那我还能怎么办
What am I supposed to do,
眼睁睁地看着他们被杀吗
Just let someone else die?
你看起来颇有压力
Whoa, hey. You seem a little stressed.
知道你需要什么吗
Hey, you know what you need?
晚上去市中心潇洒一下
A night out on the town.
晚上什么
A what now?
那些是什么
What are those?
另一个世界的大门
The gateway to another world.
卡塞尔
Castle.
他们每年有四场基金募捐会
They hold four fund-raisers a year.
上一次发生在
The last one took place a week
-在劫案发生一周前  -不
- Before the robberies began. - No.
这很不错的
It is perfect.
你没必要去查捐助者是谁
You don't have to ask who the donors are,
因为他们都将出现在那里
Because they'll all be there,
戴着他们的珠宝
Wearing their jewelry.
如果说雇员和志愿者都是清白的
If the employees and volunteers are clean
-那犯罪嫌疑人  -嫌犯
- Then our our perp... - Skell.
可能是负责派对工作的
Could be working the party.
我们可以在门口检查
And we can work the door.
就这么定了  晚上8点来接我
So it's settled. Pick me up at 8:00?
这是  这是一场非常正式的活动
Oh, it's, uh, a black-tie event.
-没问题 对吗  -当然没
- That's not a problem, is it? - Uh, no.
当然
No.
不  那件应该卖给二手商店
No, unh-unh. That one goes to the thrift store.
变色龙的缘分
Whoa! "Karma Chameleon."
萨克斯商店[第五大道豪华商店]
The girl at Saks said
女孩说亮片很流行
Fluorescent is in.
对  然后她就可以拿提成了
Well, then she was on commission.
太像展场女郎
Too "show girls"?
你知道他要做什么吗
You know what he's trying to do?
他想看我出丑
He wants to humiliate me.
蕾妮  可以去开门吗
Lanie, can you get that, please?
可以  但我回来的时候
All right, but you better not be
你最好别穿毕业舞会礼服
Wearing your prom dress when I get back.
爸爸  约会让你紧张吗
My dad, nervous for a date?
这是一次秘密行动  不是约会
It's not a date. It's an undercover operation.
麻烦你帮个忙
Would you?
不知道你为什么
I don't know why
不告诉我聚会在哪里举行
You won't tell me where the party is.
防止你也去
Because you'll show up.
是谁来了
Who was it?
快递
Delivery.
-谁寄的  -我们来看看
- From who? - Let's find out.
[咒语]
"Bippity boppity boo"?
灰姑娘  是他送来的
"Cinderella." it's from him.
拜托  那只是一件衣服
Oh, please, it's a dress.
打开它吧  小妞
Now open it up, girlfriend.
我知道  他真是够傲慢的
Oh, I knew it. He was arrogant,
但这次  这个完全
But this, this is complete-
惊艳
Stunning.
简直就是惊艳  请进请进
Simply stunning. Come in, come in.
等等
Oh, hang on. Hang on...
你看起来真美
You look incredible.
真的吗
Really?
真的  你打扮的不错
Really. You clean up nice,
贝克特探长  谢谢你  卡塞尔
Detective Beckett. Thank you, Castle.
我曾经被
I was nominated
托尼奖[百老汇]提名
For a, uh, Tony once...
不  玛莎  我可不行
Oh, no, Martha, I couldn't.
-你能行  让我看看  -太棒了
- Yes, you can. Let me - Oh, it's brilliant.
那今晚你们要去哪里
So where are you guys headed tonight?
在华道尔夫饭店[纽约最豪华旅馆]
Uh, we are going to the oh ,waldorf
他们肯定逃税漏税了
Man, these guys are guilty of tax evasion,
而不是入室抢劫
Not home invasion.
外表可以欺骗人
Appearances can be deceiving.
-礼服不错  -真适合这场合
- Nice dress. - Yeah, what there is of it.
我借你好了  埃斯波西托
I'd let you borrow it, Esposito,
但上次借你那件被撑坏了
But you stretched out the last one.
大人物
Big cheese!
里奇  里奇
Ricky! Ricky!
为什么不告诉我
Why didn't you tell me
你会来这参加聚会
You were gonna be at this shindig?
我可以带你过来的
I would've given you a ride.
刚刚决定要来  听着  市长先生
Last-minute thing. Listen, Mr. Mayor,
我想向你介绍下凯特·贝克特探长
I'd like to present to you detective Kate Beckett.
凯特·贝克特  你应该见过市长
Kate Beckett, you know the mayor.
原来这就是贝克特探长
So this is Detective Beckett.
很荣幸见到你  先生
It's an honor to meet you, sir.
就叫我鲍伯就行了
Oh, please, call me Bob.
里奇  她比你说的还要漂亮多了
Rick, she's even prettier than you said.
-借一步说话  -好的
- Excuse me a minute. - Of course.
你跟鲍伯谈论我吗
You talk about me to "Bob"?
我们一起打牌
Well, we play cards together.
而且你是我
Well, that, and you are the subject
下本书的主人公
Of my next book.
-要喝酒吗  -好  伏特加
- Can I get you a drink? - Yeah. Vodka.
很多伏特加  不过
Lots of vodka. But...
我在工作  喝水吧
I'm on duty, so... Water?
伏特加
Yeah, vodka.
两杯不掺水的伏特加马丁尼
Could I get two very stiff vodka martinis?
不要摇混
Don't shake 'em.
-只要稍微晃一下  -理查德
- Just swirl'em around a bit. - Richard.
瑞秋·马多克斯
Rachel Maddox.
我们通过电话
We spoke on the phone.
想起来了  谢谢你
Oh, and thank you very much
帮我弄到票
For getting me the tickets.
也谢谢你
Thanks for the signed
第一版签名小说拿出来拍卖
First edition for the auction.
我也想竞拍  但它对我来说
I had my eye on it, but it's probably
-太贵了
- Too rich for my blood.
保尔·雷诺兹  是你的狂热粉丝
My boyfriend, Paul Reynolds. He's a huge fan.
见到粉丝总是让我高兴
Oh, always nice to meet a fan. Hi.
别担心
Don't sweat it.
瑞秋不算什么  安妮才是部门的头
That's just Rachel, Anne's head of development.
可以说她只是看上了他的钱
She's only after his money, so to speak.
-我叫露丝  -我叫贝克
- Oh, I'm Ruthie. - Um, Beck-
我叫凯特  很高兴认识你
I'm s-I'm Kate. Nice to meet you.
你为慈善团体工作吗
Do you work for the charity?
不  但我是联合会的
No. No, but I am on the circuit.
像是乳腺癌  地雷
You know, breast cancer, land mines.
你知道最棒的是什么
Oh, you know what the best one is?
工程  你们管它叫什么来着
Um, uh, project... What do you call it?
唇部的那个  那里有许多整容外科医生  很好钓
The one with the lips. There are a lot of, uh, Plastic surgeons there - fish in a barrel.
是吗
Really?
不是说让你找我帮忙
Oh, not that you need any help from me.
我看到你线上有一条大鱼了
I see you've got a big one on the line.
稳住  凯蒂  听说他很红
Settle in, Katie. I hear he's a fighter.
抱歉  你是说卡塞尔吗
Uh-sorry, Castle?
募捐登记表上大多数女生
Oh, most of the girls on the register
都曾想钓他
Have tried to land him.
又有钱又帅气
Rich and handsome-
我们管他叫  白鲸
We call him "The White Whale."
听着  下个月我们准备让
Listen, we're having
捐款最多的几个人小聚一下
A little gathering next month for our top donors.
我们准备公开  建造新排练场的计划
We're going to unveil plans for a new rehearsal space.
如果你有空  我们希望你和
If you're free, we'd love for you and
-阿丽克西斯能来  -你认识我女儿
- Alexis to come. - You know my daughter?
我们认为尽可能多的
We make a point to know as much as we can
了解潜在捐献者
About our potential donors,
并迎合他们的趣味是很必要的
So we can match their interests with our programs.
别的地方  只要求你签张支票
So many places just ask you to write a check.
我们想让你知道
We want you to know that
你的钱用到了实处
Your money is making a difference.
-我离开一会儿可以吗  -当然
- Would you excuse me just for a second? - Sure.
太可怕了
So creepy.
没找到任何与速写相似的人
Negative on anyone matching our sketch.
卖主和员工的调查结果如何
How are we doing on vendors and staff?
目前为止还没有可疑对象
No red flags yet.
在慈善会里感觉如何
Hey, so what's it like in there?
是自助餐还是前菜刚吃完
Is it buffet or passed hors d'oeuvres?
两者兼有  你有没有看见
Both. Hey, have you seen, uh-
卡塞尔  你在做什么
Castle, what are you doing?
抱歉  但这是唯一一个
Sorry, this is the only place
我们谈话不会被偷听的地方
I knew we could talk and not be overheard.
那是当然
Sure it is.
我刚才在跟捐赠部门的
I was just talking to the head of
经理讲话  就在那儿
Uh, donor development over there...
她似乎过于了解我的事
She seems to know an awful lot about me.
她不是唯一一个
She's not the only one.
还不知道他们管你叫白鲸吧
Did you know that they call you "the white whale"?
白鲸吗
The white whale? Mm-hmm.
-不是莫比  -不是
- Not Moby- - no.
她在捐赠部门工作
She's in donor development.
了解你是她的工作
It's her job to know about you.
另外  她也没把我当做罪犯头子
Besides, she doesn't strike me
给踢出去
As a criminal mastermind.
我仍觉得我们应该再看看
Still, I think we should take a second look.
二  三  倒
Two, three... Dip.
卡塞尔  帮个忙
Castle, a little help.
那是鲍威尔
It's Powell.
那个珠宝窃贼吗
The jewel thief?
我不相信  你们两个也参加了这个
I don't believe this. The two of you are in on it?
别看我  是他的主意
Don't look at me. It was his idea.
你把我耍的团团转  不是吗
You really had me going, didn't you?
什么酒  奶酪  行事准则
The wine, the cheese, the code of conduct-
然后你又出现在这里  把我当傻子
And here you are, making me look the fool.
我只是想快活快活
I just wanted to have a bit of fun.
快活  你管你的所作所为
Fun? You call what you're doing
-叫快活  -卡塞尔  怎么了
- "Fun"? - Castle, what's going on?
他们两个合伙蒙我
They're in on it together.
就差没承认了
They've all but admitted it.
我很抱歉
I am so sorry.
-我不知道这事这么要紧  -要紧
- I had no idea it was such a big deal. -Big deal?
已经死了两个人了
Two people are dead.
死
Dead?
他在说什么
What's he talking about?
上帝啊  里克
Good lord, Rick.
你不会认为
You didn't think-
那么你们在悄悄说什么
Then... What were you two whispering about?
谢谢你们今晚莅临
Thank you all for coming tonight.
是时候让我们大家打开心扉了
Now it's time for all of us to open our hearts.
鉴于我们正要拍卖全城闻名的宝贝
As we auction off some of the city's finest items
并以慈善的名义
For one of the finest causes.
在竞拍开始前
To start the bidding,
请欢迎玛莎·罗杰斯
Please welcome Martha Rodgers.
-你做了什么  -只是个回礼
- What have you done? - Just a little payback.
感谢你们的盛情欢迎
Thank you for that warm welcome.
清单上的第一件宝物
The first item on our list
是签名的初版
Is a signed first edition
《暴风季节》  作者是
Of "Storm Season," written by...
是我的儿子  他就在那里
Well, by my son. There he is.
挥手  亲爱的  让大家看看你
Wave, darling, so everyone can see you.
太帅了  女士们  我儿子还单身
Isn't he handsome? My still-single son, ladies.
作为额外奖励  竞拍的胜者
So as a special bonus, the winning bidder
可以获得和我儿子
Will also receive an enchanting evening
共度良宵的机会
In his company.
好了  小姐们  红娘就做到这里
All right, ladies, that's the best I can do.
剩下的由你们决定
The rest is up to you.
有人开始竞拍吗
Okay, do we have an opening bid?
2500美元
$2,500!
2500  谢谢蓝裙美女
$2,500-beautiful lady in blue, thank you so much.
有出3000的吗  3000
Do we hear $3,000? $3,000?
姑娘们  别害羞
Girls, don't be shy.
有位先生竞拍了
We have a gentleman bidder.
他真是有魅力
Oh, and isn't he attractive?
天哪  我们思想真开放
Oh, my goodness, aren't we broad-minded?
有人出4000了
Oh! There we have it-$4,000.
小姐们  竞争开始了
All right, ladies,the gauntlet is down.
他是世界上最幽默
All right, this is the most witty...
现在扯平了
Now we're even.
最聪明  最有魅力的男人
Intelligent and charming man...
看  我有的是钱
Look, I have money.
不论你付多少  我都会还你
Anything you pay, I'll pay you back.
卡塞尔  门都没有
Oh, not a chance in hell, Castle.
听着
Hey, whoa, look-
募捐部女士的男朋友
There's donor girl's boyfriend.
-怎么了  -他在拍照
- So? - So he's taking pictures.
那又如何  如果我有相机我也会拍
So? I would, too, if I had a camera.
你会拍观众群吗
Of the crowd?
7000  有人出7000
$7,000! $7,000.
7000一次  7000两次
Oh, going once, going twice...
7000成交
Sold for $7,000.
雷诺兹  保尔·雷诺兹
Reynolds. Paul Reynolds.
完全符合  他记录珠宝
It's perfect. He i.d.'s the jewels
然后用她女朋友的资料
And then uses his girlfriend's research
来组建目标资料
To build profiles on the victims.
保尔·雷诺兹  也叫查德·内利斯
Paul Reynolds, A.K.A. Chad Nellie.
前科有支票诈骗  挪用公款
He served on check fraud, embezzlement,
赝品制造和大宗盗窃
Forgery and grand larceny.
没什么好害羞的
Well, it does no good to be coy.
我看到你整晚都在对我
I've seen the looks you've been throwing
-使眼色了  -我们在购物吗
- Me all night. -Shopping, are we?
保尔·雷诺兹  你因为
Paul Reynolds, you're under arrest
盗窃和预谋谋杀
On suspicion of theft and conspiracy
-被捕了  -跟我走
- To commit murder. - Let's go.
你把警徽藏在哪里的
Where was the badge?
你别管
Don't ask.
入室抢劫  武器
Yo. B&E, firearms-
抓住他绝对是个大进展
Definitely a step up for this guy.
他只是个小兵
He's just a foot soldier.
我们要找的是幕后大将
We're looking for his general.
你把裙子怎么了
What happened to the dress?
你不会以为我会穿着裙子
You didn't think I was gonna interrogate him
-审他吧  -我们希望你会
- in it, did you? - We were kinda hoping...
从我的椅子上下来  卡塞尔
Outta my chair, castle.
好
Yes.
就是说你认识他
So you know him?
在绿港监狱认识  像我这样的人
We met in green haven prison. A guy like me-
他们会在里面把我弄死
You know they've would've eaten me alive in there.
但是他在里面罩着我
But he looked out for me in the yard.
他们都怕他  连警卫也是
They-they were all afraid of him, even the guards.
他出狱了  不知怎么找上我
And when he got out, he found me. I don't know how.
他让我打入慈善团体内部
So it was his idea to infiltrate the charity.
我那时候就已经在和瑞秋交往了
I was already seeing Rachel at the time.
我是说  我本想直接拒绝
I mean, I was trying to go straight,
但他说这是我欠他的
But he said that I owed him.
所以你就把所有捐款者资料都给他了
And so you just fed him all the top donors.
他所要的一切都在
Everything he needed was already
档案里了  姓名  地址
In the dossiers- names, addresses.
我为所有的珠宝拍照
I took photographs of all their jewelry,
把他们都放进闪存里
Put it all on a flash drive,
但他贪得无厌
But he wanted more and more.
警长  在他打死那个人以后
Detective, after he beat that guy to death,
我告诉他我想退出了
I told him I wanted out.
但他说一旦我退出
But he said that if I quit,
除非我把在狱中欠他的  全还回来
That he'd do everything he saved me from in prison.
不止对我还要对瑞秋下手
He'd do it to me and Rachel.
那就告诉我哪里能找到他
Then tell me where I can find him.
卡塞尔  作为你的朋友
Castle, as a friend,
我警告你别下车
I am asking you not to leave this car,
因为你的大胆行为会
'Cause your little hardy boy act...
会惹来杀身之祸  我知道了
Is gonna get me killed, I know.
更可能让你的同伴牺牲
More like get one of them killed,
我可不想良心不安  懂了
And I can't have that on my conscience. Understood?
万一我想小便怎么办
What if I have to pee?
走  快走
Go, go, go...
纽约警察  我们有搜查证
NYPD! We have a warrant!
看  他的咖啡
Look, his coffee.
还是温的  他可能刚走
Still warm. Must've just missed him.
收到
And roger.
1708之后  请告诉我你的位置
Can I have your, uh, next position after 1-7-0-8?
各部门  我是卡塞尔探员
This is detective Castle to all units.
取消支援
That's a negatory on the backup.
我来对付这无耻的家伙
This dirtbag's all mine.
看来我们找对地方了
Looks like we got the right place.
站住  警察
Stop, police!
从后面跟他出去
Follow him out back!
上帝
God.
下车
Out of the car!
我  她让我别下车
I- she told me I actually have to stay in here-
-下车  -好的
- Out of the car now! - Okay, okay,
我出来了  我这就出来
Okay, here I come. I'm coming.
上帝
God.
继续啊
Go ahead...
我得练练身手
I need the practice.
抓住他了  起来
We got him. Get up.
我本不想下车的  真的
I tried to stay in the car. I really did.
他打了我的脸  你知道吗
He hit me in the face, you know.
是的  我看见了
Yeah, I saw that.
那个  "继续啊  我得练练身手"
That, uh, "go ahead, I need the practice"-
那真经典
That was classic.
卡塞尔
Castle!
抱歉
Sorry.
其它几件仍作为证物保留
The other pieces are still in evidence,
但我觉得把这个还你并无大碍
But I don't see the harm in returning this.
你怎么挺过去的
How do you get over it?
不会挺过去
You don't.
但某天你会醒悟  然后发现
But one day you'll wake up and you'll find
你已经可以整天带着它了
That you don't mind carrying it around with you.
至少我只到了这一步
At least that's as far as I've come.
谢谢你  探长
Thank you, detective.
我叫凯特
My name's Kate.
一旦你想找人倾诉
If you ever need to talk...
亲爱的  有客到
Darling, we have a visitor.
真勇敢  卡塞尔
Oh, pretty butch, Castle.
我也觉得  来  挑张凳子坐
I know, right? Come, grab a chair.
不  我只是来归还
Oh, no, I just came to return your
-你妈妈的首饰  -你救了我
- Mom's jewelry. - You saved my life.
我至少能给你做几个蛋吃
The least I can do is make you some eggs.
不  真的  我得走了
No, really, I - I- I have to get going.
不行  你就坐这儿
Nonsense! You sit down right here,
告诉我们昨天发生了什么
Tell us all about last night.
我们只听过他的版本
We've only heard his version.
好的
All right, um...
-我从走红地毯开始讲行吗  -可以
- Shall I begin at the red carpet? - Yes, please.
我们一出来
So we came out...